Seamus Heaney papers, 1951-2004
Emory University
- Writings by others, 1964-2004, Series 2; Boxes 65 – 73 and OP9
  - Other writings, 1964-2004, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 68 - 73; OP9
    - Simmons, James, "Naming Your Pleasure," "Gentlemen's Agreement," "The Island Again," poems, photocopied typescript (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Sleigh, Tom, Waking, poetry collection, photocopied typescript, ca. 1990 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Smith, John T., Brave New World, poetry collection with letter, typescript, 1991 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Sommer, Jason, Lifting the Stone, poetry collection, photocopied typescript (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Sommer, Jason, Lifting the Stone, photocopied proofs with cover letter, 1991 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Sommer, Jason, "Singing Something," "Homecoming," "Fighting with My Father," poems, typescript (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Steele, Peter, "Attention to Feeling: Derek Mahon's Past," essay, typescript (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Strachan, Pat, eulogy delivered at memorial service for Anne Sullivan, 30 November 1995, photocopied typescript (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - Summerfield, Geoffrey, "All at Sea," story for Michael and Christopher Heaney, typescript signed by author (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - Summerfield, Geoffrey, "On Receiving 'A Rich Hour,'" poem for Seamus and Marie, typescript, signed by author, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - Summerfield, Geoffrey, "Treading on Holy Ground," essay, photocopied typescript with revisions (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - Tagliabue, John, four poems, typescript, with ACS and ANS and envelope, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - Temple, Elizabeth, "The Picture Vanishes or The Keeper's Story," and Seal Woman," poems, photocopied typescript, 1992 (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - Tuteur, Mary, "Egg-plant Madonna," "Snake Dreams," "On Earth," student poems, typescript (Box 73, Folder 22)
    - de Valera, Terry, Rhymes of Remembrance, poetry collection with TLS from author, photocopied typescript, 1998 (Box 73, Folder 23)
    - Vazivani, Rectika, three student poems, carbon typescript (Box 73, Folder 24)
    - Vendler, Helen, prepublication holograph notes for Government of the Tongue, ca. late 1980s (Box 73, Folder 25)
    - Wall, Alan, After Danae, poetry collection, photocopied typescript with cover letter (Box 73, Folder 26)
    - Wallace-Crabbe, Chris, collection of poems, typescript and photocopied typescript, 1991-2000 and undated (Box 73, Folder 27)
    - Weeks-Pearson, Tony, "The Bridge," novella, photocopied typescript with ALS, 1999 (Box 73, Folder 28)
    - Wheelock, C. Webster, "The Winter Lingers," "Irish Poet's Reading," poems, photocopied typescript, 1985 (Box 73, Folder 29)
    - Williamson, Alan, "The Values of Contemporary European Poetry," photocopied typescript (Box 73, Folder 30)
    - Wyley, Edna, "Diary of a Fatman," poem, photocopied typescript, 2000 (Box 73, Folder 31)
    - Zinsmeister, J., "Ketchikan," poem, typescript, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 32)
    - Unidentified poems (Box 73, Folder 33)
    - Unidentified fragments of prose (Box 73, Folder 34)
- Printed material, 1958-2003, Series 3; Boxes 74 – 88; OP10 – OP13
  The printed materials consist of writings by Seamus Heaney, writings about him, reviews of his writings, and miscellaneous collected printed materials from 1958-2003. Writings by Heaney (1965-2003) include poems printed and reprinted in periodical literature, essays written by Heaney, reviews of other authors' writings, proofs of work being published, and translations done by Heaney. Writings about Heaney (1966-2002) include news articles; promotional materials for his writings, readings, and lectures; and cartoons, catalogs, postcards, and programs which relate to Heaney. The series also contains many printed reviews of Heaney's writings which appeared in newspapers and literary publications from 1966-2002. These reviews are primarily in the form of clippings.
  Also present in the series are printed materials collected by Seamus Heaney from 1958-2003. These collected materials consist of writings by others, including Alfred Alcorn, Gerald Dawes, Dana Gioia, John Montague, Hayden Murphy, and Connor Cruise O'Brien; as well as miscellaneous programs, broadsides, pamphlets and leaflets.
  Organized into four subseries: (3.1) Writings by Seamus Heaney, (3.2) Writings about Seamus Heaney, (3.3) Reviews and (3.4) Collected printed materials.
  - Writings by Seamus Heaney, 1965-2003, Subseries 3.1; Boxes 74
    Scope and content note
    The subseries consists of a variety of Heaney's writings printed in programs, newspapers, literary journals, cards and book jackets from 1965-2003.
    - "Peter Street at Bankside," poem printed in "Program for the Laying of the Foundation Stone of the New Theatre at Ridgeway Street, Belfast, by Austin Clarke," 12 June 1965 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - "The Barn," reprinted in Today and Yesterday in Northern Ireland, BBC Radio Program Guide for Schools, Autumn Term, 1966 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - "Victorian Guitar," The Listener, 18 January 1968 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - "Turkeys Observed" [from Death of a Naturalist], reprinted in The Irish Times, 24 December 1968 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - "Shore Woman," The Irish Press, 1 March 1969 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - "Seven Poems by Seamus Heaney," ["Sernades," "Midnight," "Navvy," "First Calf," "Medallion," "Icon," "Idyll"], The Listener, 4 September 1969 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - "Adriotest of Makers," review of Thank You, Fog by W.W. Auden and Poetry Introduction 3 and The Third Book of Criticism by Randall Jarrell, photocopied from The Education Times (Dublin), 6 February 1975 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - "A Dream of Jealousy," (previously unpublished poem) and work sheets of four poems in North, printed in Quarto, volume 2, number 1, November 1975, photocopies (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - "Strange Fruit," (from North, 1976), reprinted in The New York Review of Books, 18 March 1976, p. 7 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - "The Language of Exile," review of The Star-Apple Kingdom by Derek Walcott, Parnassus, Fall/Winter 1979, pp. 5-11, photocopy (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - "A Tale of Two Islands: Reflections on the Irish Poetry Revival," offprint from Irish Studies, volume 1 1980 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - "Current Unstated Assumptions about Poetry," reprint from Critical Enquiry, volume 7, number 4, Summer 1981 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Station Island, verses excerpted and reprinted in Radio Times, 11 October 1984 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - "An Ulster Twilight" from Station Island with translation into Catalan by J.M. Jauma, 1985 [includes holograph notes from translator and from Seamus Heaney] (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - "Fra Samvittighedens Republik," ["The Republic of Conscience"], printed in Debat, 7 July 1986 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Untitled poem for Marie Bullock, Poetry Pilot, February 1987 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - "Brodsky's Nobel: What the Applause Was About," article photocopied from The New York Times Book Review, 8 November 1987 (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - "The Impact of Translation" [edited version of an article included in The Government of the Tongue], END: Journal of European Nuclear Disarmament, Issue 33, February-March 1988, pp. 22-24 (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - "The Voice of the Bard," essay, Antaeus, Spring 1988 (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - "Extempore Effusion on Missing Rosemary's Party," privately printed poem with holograph note signed Rosa, 28 February 1995 (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - "David Thomson," [obituary], The Independent, [1988] (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - "New Worlds," In the Prison of His Days [a miscellany for Nelson Mandala on his 70th birthday], 1988, photocopy (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - "The Indefatigable Hoof-taps," article regarding Sylvia Plath, The Times Literary Supplement, 5-11 February 1988, pp. 134, 143-4 (Box 74, Folder 23)
    - "Henry Pearson: In the Middle of the Field," insert for exhibition brochure, Columbia Museum of Art, 25 July 1988 (Box 74, Folder 24)
    - The Government of the Tongue, galley corrections, 29 November 1988 (Box 74, Folder 25)
    - "A Field Day for the Irish," photocopied from The Times, 5 December 1988 (Box 74, Folder 26)
    - "In the Midst of the Force-field," article regarding W.B. Yeats, photocopied from The Irish Times, 28 January 1989 (Box 74, Folder 27)
    - "Two Poems by Seamus Heaney: 'A Latch' and 'A Window,'" photoset by Computer Graphics for Times Literary Supplement, 10 October 1989 (Box 74, Folder 28)
    - "Une tasse d'eau," French translation by Ann Bernard Kearney and Florence Lafon, reprinted in Figaro Litteraire from Poems 1966-1984, 1 September 1989 (Box 74, Folder 29)
    - Book cover quote, An Artificial Wilderness by Sven Birkerts, paperback edition, 1990 (Box 74, Folder 30)
    - Excerpt from The Cure at Troy: A Version of Sophocles' Philoctetes, reprinted on card sent to friends and members of the Fellowship of Reconciliation, ca. 1990 (Box 74, Folder 31)
    - "The Ship in the Air," from Lightenings, reprinted with photograph of Seamus Heaney, photocopied from Edge, number 3, Autumn, 1990 (Box 74, Folder 32)
    - "The Ash Plant" (from Seeing Things, 1991), reprinted in Los Angeles Times, 9 February 1992 (Box 74, Folder 33)
    - "I Bambini Della Ferrovia," poem card, translation into Italian by Gilberto Sacerdoti, 1993 (Box 74, Folder 33a)
    - "Light Finally Enters the Black Hole," article photocopied from Sunday Tribune, 4 September 1994 (Box 74, Folder 34)
    - "An Aisling in the Burren," p. 9, (from Station Island), and "Postscript," p.15, Burren College of Art catalog, ca. 1994 (Box 74, Folder 35)
    - "Mycenae Lookout," Times Literary Supplement, proof, 1994 (Box 74, Folder 36)
    - Untitled poem for Prof. Ronald Schuchard, reprinted in Innovation with Tradition: Newsletter of the University of London Library, no. 1, Spring 1994 [photocopy] (Box 74, Folder 37)
    - "Doubletake," two verses, reprinted from The Cure at Troy, Christmas card printed for Sister Sarah Clarke, ca. 1995 (Box 74, Folder 38)
    - "Frandskap," printed as part of a news article, [ SDS, 10 December 1995] (Box 74, Folder 39)
    - Commencement address, The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, number 91 of 500 copies, 12 May 1996 (Box 74, Folder 40)
    - Letter printed in "A.E. Houseman: Poet and Scholar, Westminster Abbey, September 1996," collection of letters to support admission of A.E. Houseman to Poet's Corner at Westminster Abbey, p. 27 (Box 74, Folder 41)
    - "The Morning Light," poem for Tony O'Malley from the Irish of Brian Merriman, printed in "Tony O'Malley: Recent Canvasses & the Good Friday Paintings," exhibition catalog, RHA Gallagher Gallery, 1997 (Box 74, Folder 42)
    - "The Last Survivor" [translation of Beowulf, lines 2241-70], The Times Literary Supplement, number 4937, 14 November 1997 (Box 74, Folder 43)
    - "Lightenings," excerpt from Seeing Things (1991), reprinted in Pushkin Prizes, 10th Anniversary Dinner program, 25 November 1997 (Box 74, Folder 44)
    - "The Reciprocity of Tears," article photocopied from The Irish Times, 22 August 1998 (Box 74, Folder 45)
    - "On First Looking into Ted Hughes's Birthday Letters," poem photocopied from The New Yorker, 5 October 1998 (Box 74, Folder 46)
    - Beowulf specimen, proofs, p. 21, 5 July 1999 (Box 74, Folder 47)
    - "Vitruviana," [for Felim Eagan], printed as an insert for Christmas card sent by Felim Eagan, ca. December 1999 (Box 74, Folder 48)
    - "At Toomebridge" and "The Augean Stables," College Green, September 2000 (Box 74, Folder 49)
    - The Midnight Verdict, photocopied text for paperback edition with letter from Peter Fallon, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 50)
    - "Shoreline," excerpt from Door into the Dark, proposed text and layout for 2001 Centurian Medal, telefacsimile, 15 November 2000 (Box 74, Folder 51)
    - "Follower," 1966, in Arrows of Desire: A Draft of Poems for Series II, Optic Nerve Productions, February 2003 (Box 74, Folder 52)
    - "The Power of Poetry," excerpts from commencement address at Emory University, 12 May 2003, printed from the Internet, originally published 16 June 2003 (Box 74, Folder 53)
    - "…is always political," book review, Essays on Politics and Literature by Bernard Crick, photocopied from unknown source, undated (Box 74, Folder 54)
    - "Dimitri, Hadzi," comments on Hadzi's sculptures printed on small cards, undated (Box 74, Folder 55)
    - "In a Basilica," poem reprinted in unknown source from Observer, unknown date (Box 74, Folder 56)
    - "Morte d'un Naturaliste, French translation, photocopied from Lettre Internationale, unknown date (Box 74, Folder 57)
    - "Un Vis de Gelozie" ["A Dream of Jealousy"], translated into Romanian, Suplimentul literar-artistic al Seinteii tineretului, unknown date (Box 74, Folder 58)
    - "The Vulgar Muse," review of The Faber Book of Vernacular Verse, edited by Tom Paulin, photocopy from unknown source, undated (Box 74, Folder 59)
  - Writings about Seamus Heaney, 1965-2004, Subseries 3.2; Boxes 75 - 79; OP 10-12
    Writings about Seamus Heaney consist of articles and essays published by others including Seamus Deane, Terrance Des Pres, Theo Dorgan, Darcy O'Brien, and Bernard O'Donoghue from 1965-2002. Also included are clippings taken from periodical literature (1965-2002); flyers, leaflets and posters publicizing Heaney readings, writings and lectures; and a variety of cartoons, catalogs, post cards and programs, all of which relate to Heaney.
    - Articles and essays
    - Ross, Alan, "Poetry: Ginsburg, Snyder, Heaney, Ramanujan," London Magazine, August 1966 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Clarke, Austin, "Seamus Heaney, Contemporary Poets, ca. mid 1970s (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - McCormack, W.J., "Straight Lines Become Circles: The Poetry of Seamus Heaney and Derek Mahon," Acorn, Spring 1972 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - "Top 100," Irish America, March 1972 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Silkin, Jon, "Bedding the Locale," New Blackfriars, March 1973 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Bidwell, Bruce, "The Soft Grip on the Sick Place: The Bogland Poetry of Seamus Heaney," The Dublin Magazine, Autumn/Winter 1973/1974 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Brown, Terence, "Contemporary Irish Poetry," Ireland Today, number 884, March 1976 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Fitzgerald, Robert, "Seamus Heaney: An Appreciation," The New Republic, 27 March 1976 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Sharratt, Bernard, "Memories of Dying: The Poetry of Seamus Heaney," New Blackfriars, volume 57, number 674, July 1976 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Sharratt, Bernard, "Memories of Dying: The Poetry of Seamus Heaney II," New Blackfriars, volume 57, number 675, August 1976, with uncorrected galley (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Broadbridge, Edward, editor, Seamus Heaney, Skoleradioen, 1977 [photocopy] (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - O'Brien, Darcy," In Ireland After A Portrait," photocopied from Approaches to Joyce's Portrait, edited by Thomas F. Staley and Bernard Benstock, 1977 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Donoghue, Denis, "Now and in Ireland: The Literature of Trouble," Hibernia, 11 May 1978 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Dorgan, Theo, "Wedding Guests on the Anniversary," [for Seamus and Marie], poem sheet, inscribed and signed, August 1990 (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - Mills, Georgina, "Interview with Seamus Heaney," Strawberry Fare, Autumn 1980 (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - Schirmer, Gregory A. "Seamus Heaney's Salvation in Surrender," Erie-Ireland, Winter 1980 (Box 75, Folder 16)
    - Waterman, Andrew, "Somewhere, Out There, Beyond: The Poetry of Seamus Heaney and Derek Mahon," Poetry Nation Review, volume 8, number 1, 1981 (Box 75, Folder 17)
    - Des Pres, Terrance, "Seamus Heaney: Politics and Poetics," Harper's, March 1981 (Box 75, Folder 18)
    - Deane, Seamus, "Contemporary Writers Series: 1, Seamus Heaney," Ireland Today, number 977, June 1981 (Box 75, Folder 19)
    - McKeen, Catherine, "Seamus Heaney: The Eloquent Earth," America, June 20, 1981 (Box 75, Folder 20)
    - Hill, Mark and Eric Hadley, "Seamus Heaney and Translation: Two Articles: Seamus Heaney and Charles Baudelaire," by Hill and "Heaney and Dante" by Hadley, The Present Tense, Winter 1981 (Box 75, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous foreign language articles about Seamus Heaney, 1981-1989 and undated (Box 75, Folder 22)
    - Parkinson, Thomas, "Serious Work: The Poetry and Prose of Seamus Heaney," The Southern Review, Spring 1982 (Box 75, Folder 23)
    - Mahony, Phillip, "Seamus Heaney and the Violence in Northern Ireland," The Journal of Irish Literature, September 1982 (Box 75, Folder 24)
    - Kearney, Timothy, "'Befitting Emblems of Adversity': Seamus Heaney, The Poet and the Troubles," Threshold, Winter 1982 (Box 75, Folder 25)
    - Quinlan, Kieran, "Unearthing a Terrible Beauty: Seamus Heaney's Victims of Violence," World Literature Today, Summer 1983 (Box 75, Folder 26)
    - Kelly, Conor, "Seamus Heaney: Naming His Nation," Magill, volume 7, number 5, Christmas 1983 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Johnston, Conor, "Poetry and Politics: Responses to the Northern Ireland Crisis in the Poetry of John Montague, Derek Mahon, and Seamus Heaney," Poesis, 1984 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Dodsworth, Martin, "Heaney's Poetry: Ambiguous Space," Poetry Nation Review, volume 12, number 2, 1985 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Grant, Damian, "The Voice of History in British Poetry, 1970-1984," E'tudes Anglaises," volume 38, number 2, 1985 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - McClatchy, J.D., "Poetry Chronicle," The Hudson Review, ca. 1985 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Buttel, Robert, "Seamus Heaney," Dictionary of Literary Biography, volume 40, 1985 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Lehman, David and Donna Foote, "The Ulster Renaissance," Newsweek, 12 May 1986 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Lehr, Dick, "Schultz Warns against U.S. Isolation," The Boston Globe, 6 September 1986 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Beisch, June, "An Interview with Seamus Heaney," The Literary Review, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Murphy, Daniel, et al, "Seamus Heaney," Education and the Arts: The Educational Autobiographies of Contemporary Irish Poets, Novelists, Dramatists, Musicians, Painters and Sculptors, Trinity College, Dublin, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Furomoto, Taketoshi, "A Reading of Seamus Heaney's 'Kinship,'" Kobe Miscellany, 1988 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Toibin, Colm, "Special Award: Seamus Heaney, Poet's Progress," The Sunday Independent, Color Extra, ca. 1989 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Waterman, Andrew, "Keep It in the Six Counties, Heaney!" Poetry Nation Review, volume 15, number 6, 1989 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Crowder, Ashby Bland, "Heaney's 'Elegy for a Still-Born Child,'" Winter 1989 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Dunn, Douglas, "The Topical Muse: On Contemporary Poetry," The Kenneth Allcott Lectures [number 6], delivered 22 March 1990, with letter from the author (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Cosgrove, Brian, "Seamus Heaney and the Claims of Irish Nationalism," Studies: An Irish Quarterly Review, Autumn 1990 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Midzunoe, Yuichi, Japanese Translation of Seamus Heaney's 'Glanmore Sonnets' and Others, 1990 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Bayley, John, "Godmother of the Salmon," London Review of Books, 9 July 1992 (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Anonymous, "Seamus Heaney," The International Who's Who, 1992-1998 (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Crowder, Ashley Bland, "Seamus Heaney's Schoolboy: 'Death of a Naturalist,' Birth of a Moralist," Poets and Critics, Their Means and Meanings, 1993 (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - O'Donoghue, Bernard, "Our Nobel Laureate," Oxford Magazine, 1995 (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Fumagalli, Maria Christina, "The Eternal Fountain of Poetic Imagination: Seamus Heaney's Translation of Juan de la Cruz's 'Cantar de Alma que se Huelga de Conoscer a Dios por Fee,'" Agenda, volume 35, number 2, Summer 1997 (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - O'Donoghue, Bernard, review of Seamus Heaney by Helen Vendler, reprinted from Essays in Criticism, volume 55, number 1, January 2000 (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - Anonymous, "Seamus Heaney," biography printed in the program for the Second Meeting of Poets, Krakow, 10-13 November 2000 (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - Reddy, Srikanth, "The Bastion of Sensation: Stationing the Self in the Poetry of Seamus Heaney," Journal x, ca. Spring 2001 (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - Midzunoe, Yuichi, "Quest for Identities in Modern Irish Poems," unidentified source, undated (Box 76, Folder 26)
    - Clippings: news articles
    - 1965-1966 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 1967 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - 1968 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 1970 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 1972 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - 1976 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 1977 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - 1978 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - 1979 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - 1980 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - 1981 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - 1982 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - 1983 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - 1984 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - 1985 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - 1986 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - 1987 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - 1988 (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - 1989 (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - 1990 (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - 1991 (Box 77, Folder 22)
    - 1992 (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - 1993 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - 1994 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - 1995 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - 1996 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - 1997 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - 1998 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - 1999 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - 2000 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - 2002 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Undated (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Promotional material
    - Door into the Dark, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Lectures, 1974-2002 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Readings, 1978-2004 and undated (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Readings, posters, 1985-2002 and undated (Box OP10)
    - Films, ca. 1980s (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Poems, 1965-1975, 1980 (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - Preoccupations, 1980 (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - Field Work, 1981 (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Selected Poems, 1982 (Box 78, Folder 18)
    - A Poetry Writing Workshop with Seamus Heaney, College of Notre Dame, leaflet, 1983 (Box 78, Folder 19)
    - Station Island, 1984 (Box 78, Folder 20)
    - Sweeney Astray, 1985 (Box 78, Folder 21)
    - Sweeney Astray, book jacket, 1985 (Box OP11)
    - Four Poets for St. Magnus, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 22)
    - "Voices and Visions," television course, ca. 1987 (Box 78, Folder 23)
    - Boylston Prize Speaking Contest, Seamus Heaney, judge, 1988 (Box 78, Folder 24)
    - A Curse at Troy, drama, 1990-1995 (Box 78, Folder 25)
    - Field Day Anthology of Irish Writing, 1981 (Box 78, Folder 26)
    - Keeping Going, 1993 (Box 78, Folder 27)
    - Exhibitions, 1995 (Box 78, Folder 28)
    - The Redress of Poetry, 1995 (Box 78, Folder 29)
    - The Spirit Level, 1996 (Box 78, Folder 30)
    - The Spirit Level, poster signed by Heaney (Box OP12)
    - Other printed material
    - Cartoon, The Chronicle of Higher Education, undated (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Catalogs (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Poems, 1976-1984 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Postcards (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Programs, 1968-1989 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Programs, 1990s (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Programs, 2000-2002; undated (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous items (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Reviews, 1966-2002, Subseries 3.3; Boxes 80 - 83
    The subseries consists of printed reviews of writings by Seamus Heaney from 1966-2002 and a small number of general review articles relating to Heaney and his work.
    Arranged in chronological order by publication date.
    - Death of a Naturalist, 1966 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Eleven Poems, 1966 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Door into the Dark, 1969 [1 of 2] (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Door into the Dark, 1969 [2 of 2] (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Soundings, 1972 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Wintering Out, 1972 [1 of 2] (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Wintering Out, 1972 [2 of 2] (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - North, 1972 [1 of 3] (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - North, 1972 [2 of 3] (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - North, 1972 [3 of 3] (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Stations, 1975 (Box 81, Folder 2)